A Guide to the John A. Hartford Foundation records, Grants, Series 3 FA1218
Rockefeller Archive Center
John A. Hartford Foundation records, Grants, Series 3
1954-1999
Rockefeller Archive Center
John A. Hartford Foundation
FA1218
42.7 Cubic Feet 112 letter document boxes and 1 3x5 card file.
Scope and Contents note
This series contains grant files from 1954 to 1999. During the late 1970s to mid-1980s, the John A. Hartford Foundation underwent a self-described transition period, during which it examined and redefined its grant-making programs. As a result, in a specialized program from 1980 to 1983, JAHF funded a limited number of grants focused on energy conservation for institutions. These grant files are located in Series 3, Boxes 313 to 318.
Then in 1985, JAHF distributed a nationwide request for proposals for its newly established focus on geriatric healthcare, announcing that 10 grants for a maximum of $500,000 each would be awarded. The response to the RFP exceed the foundation's expectations, and thus JAHF had to decline a large majority of the proposals. Files on these declinations are in Series 3, Boxes 293 to 299, Boxes 324 to 336, and Boxes 348 to 349.
Lastly, the series also contains files on the establishment and administration of the John A. and George L. Hartford fellowship program from 1979 to 1986.
Biographical/Historical Note
The John A. Hartford Foundation (JAHF) was established in 1929 by brothers John and George Hartford, sons of the founder of the Great Atlantic & Pacific Tea Company (A&P). The foundation is a private, nonpartisan philanthropy dedicated to improving the care of older adults. For its first several decades, the foundation broadly supported clinical medical research. By 1982, it began to focus solely on geriatric healthcare. In 2015, JAHF paid out $20.2 million on a total of 80 active grants and committed $25.3 million to 24 new grants projects, all focused on the care of older adults.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The John A. Hartford Foundation records were donated to RAC by JAHF in 2014. Record transfers to RAC began in 2014 and continue as needed.
Arrangement
Arranged as received
Other Finding Aids
For Series 1 of the John A. Hartford Foundation records, see http://dimes.rockarch.org/FA771/collection
For Series 2 of the John A. Hartford Foundation records, see http://dimes.rockarch.org/FA1137/collection
For Series 4 of the John A. Hartford Foundation records, see http://dimes.rockarch.org/FA1296/collection
For Series 5 of the John A. Hartford Foundation records, see http://dimes.rockarch.org/FA1297/collection
For Series 6 of the John A. Hartford Foundation records, see http://dimes.rockarch.org/FA1326/collection
For Series 7 of the John A. Hartford Foundation records, see http://dimes.rockarch.org/FA1138/collection
- Grants, 1908-1999; 3
  - George Washington University National Health Policy Forum: J. Miller Jones (91-261), 1991-1995 (Box 238, Folder 1734-1736)
  - Harvard Community Health Plan: D. Berwick (87-020), 1987-1991 (Box 238, Folder 1737-1739)
  - Harvard Community Health Plan: D. Berwick (88-283), 1988-1992 (Box 239, Folder 1740-1742)
  - Institute for Healthcare Improvement: D. Berwick (92-023), 1992-1995 (Box 239, Folder 1743-1745)
  - Health Research, Inc.: R. Sweeney (93-046), 1993-1996 (Box 240, Folder 1746-1750)
  - University of California, San Francisco: H. Luft (90-208), 1990-1995 (Box 240, Folder 1751-1753)
  - University of Michigan: L. McMahon (87-378), 1987-1992 (Box 241, Folder 1754-1756)
  - University of Pennsylvania: M. Pauly (88-171), 1988-1991 (Box 241, Folder 1757-1758)
  - University of Pennsylvania: M. Pauly (90-288), 1990-1994 (Box 241, Folder 1759-1760)
  - University of Pennsylvania: M. Pauly (90-288), 1990-1994 (Box 242, Folder 1761-1762)
  - Vermont Health Care Information Consortium: J. Taylor (92-313), 1992-1996 (Box 242, Folder 1763-1766)
  - Institute of Medicine: E. Bond (86-124), 1986-1987 (Box 242, Folder 1767)
  - Institute of Medicine: E. Bond (86-124), 1986-1987 (Box 243, Folder 1768-1769)
  - Institute of Medicine: B. Gray (87-343), 1987-1990 (Box 243, Folder 1770-1772)
  - Institute of Medicine: R. Dick (89-277), 1989-1991 (Box 243, Folder 1773-1774)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics: J. Connelly (81-169), 1981-1984 (Box 244, Folder 1775-1777)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics: J. Connelly (83-185), 1983-1987 (Box 244, Folder 1778-1781)
  - American Institute of Medical Preventics: R. Gordon (85-319), 1985-1992 (Box 245, Folder 1782-1784)
  - Ohio Corporation for Health Information: D. Shaller (92-295), 1992-1994 (Box 245, Folder 1785-1788)
  - Ohio Corporation for Health Information: D. Shaller (92-295), 1992-1994 (Box 246, Folder 1789)
  - Ohio Corporation for Health Information: W. Petrarca (94-114), 1994-1998 (Box 246, Folder 1790-1795)
  - Ohio Corporation for Health Information: W. Petrarca (94-114), 1994-1998 (Box 247, Folder 1796-1799)
  - University Hospitals of Cleveland: C. Landefeld (92-307), 1992-1996 (Box 247, Folder 1800-1802)
  - The Rand Corporation: E. McGlynn (93-259), 1993-1998 (Box 248, Folder 1803-1811)
  - The Rand Corporation: E. McGlynn (93-259), 1993-1998 (Box 249, Folder 1812-1816)
  - University of California Los Angeles: L. Breslow (92-112), 1992-1995 (Box 250, Folder 1817-1824)
  - University of California Los Angeles: L. Breslow (92-112), 1992-1995 (Box 251, Folder 1825-1829)
  - University of California Los Angeles: L. Breslow (94-119), 1994-1998 (Box 251, Folder 1830-1832)
  - University of California Los Angeles: L. Breslow (94-119), 1994-1998 (Box 252, Folder 1833-1840)
  - University of California Los Angeles: R. Brooks (82-529), 1982-1985 (Box 253, Folder 1841-1848)
  - Health Care Purchasers Association of Puget Sound: A. Castell (90-269), 1990-1992 (Box 254, Folder 1849-1853)
  - Health Care Purchasers Association of Puget Sound: A. Castell (91-280), 1991-1994 (Box 254, Folder 1854-1856)
  - Health Care Purchasers Association of Puget Sound: A. Castell (91-280), 1991-1994 (Box 255, Folder 1857-1862)
  - Iowa CHMIS: S. Gregan (95-110), 1995-1998 (Box 255, Folder 1863-1864)
  - Iowa CHMIS: S. Gregan (95-110), 1995-1998 (Box 256, Folder 1865-1866)
  - St. Joseph Healthcare System: L. Anker (92-303), 1992-1997 (Box 256, Folder 1867-1871)
  - St. Joseph Healthcare System: L. Anker (92-303), 1992-1997 (Box 257, Folder 1872-1875)
  - Rochester Area Hospitals Corporation: J. Block (no grant number), 1981-1990 (Box 257, Folder 1876-1879)
  - Rochester Area Hospitals Corporation: J. Block (no grant number), 1981-1990 (Box 258, Folder 1880)
  - Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations: D. O'Leary (87-040), 1987-1991 (Box 258, Folder 1881-1884)
  - InterStudy: H. Wetzler (91-206), 1991-1993 (Box 258, Folder 1885-1886)
  - MedCenters Health Plan: S. Leatherman (87-069), 1987-1989 (Box 259, Folder 1887-1891)
  - MidSouth Health Care Alliance: G. Smith (95-075), 1995-1996 (Box 259, Folder 1892)
  - Memphis Business Group on Health: D. Miller (91-207), 1991-1994 (Box 259, Folder 1893)
  - Memphis Business Group on Health: D. Miller (91-207), 1991-1994 (Box 260, Folder 1894-1896)
  - Memphis Business Group on Health: D. Miller (93-133), 1993-1995 (Box 260, Folder 1897-1899)
  - Columbia University: P. Clayton (94-118), 1994-1999 (Box 260, Folder 1900)
  - Columbia University: P. Clayton (94-118), 1994-1999 (Box 261, Folder 1901-1903)
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (93-263), 1993-1997 (Box 261, Folder 1904-1907)
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (93-263), 1993-1997 (Box 262, Folder 1908-1912)
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-041), 1995-1997 (Box 262, Folder 1913-1914)
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-041), 1995-1997 (Box 263, Folder 1915-1917)
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-297), 1995-1999 (Box 263, Folder 1918-1921)
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-297), 1995-1999 (Box 264, Folder 1922-1928)
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-297), 1995-1999 (Box 265, Folder 1929-1932)
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-319), 1995-1999 (Box 265, Folder 1933-1936)
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-319) Separated media "PRISM" Application (February), 1995; 2014:023:017; 4 3.5-inch computer disks
    Conditions Governing Access
    Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. Access copy currently unavailable. To request an access surrogate be made, please contact an archivist.
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-319) Separated media "PRISM" Documentation
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-319) Separated media "PRISM" Workshop Powerpoint Presentation
  - Foundation for Health Care Quality: R. Rubin (95-319) Separated media "PRISM" Application (March)
  - Electronic Frontier Foundation, Inc.: J. Goldman (94-130), 1994-1995 (Box 266, Folder 1937)
  - County of Monroe: K. Naples (87-241), 1987-1990 (Box 266, Folder 1938-1943)
  - County of Monroe: K. Naples (87-241), 1987-1990 (Box 267, Folder 1944-1946)
  - County of Monroe: K. Naples (90-081), 1990-1994 (Box 267, Folder 1947-1951)
  - County of Monroe: K. Naples (90-081), 1990-1994 (Box 268, Folder 1952-1956)
  - Monroe County Long Term Care Program, Inc.: G. Eggert (92-242), 1992 (Box 268, Folder 1957)
  - Public Responsibility in Medicine: J. Rachlin (96-076), 1996-1999 (Box 269, Folder 1958-1964)
    - Public Responsibility in Medicine: J. Rachlin (96-076) Separated media "IRB and health services" audio cassette, circa 1997; 2014:023:018; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 9973)
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact an RAC archivist for further information.
  - Public Responsibility in Medicine: J. Rachlin (96-076), 1996-1999 (Box 270, Folder 1965-1970)
  - Public Responsibility in Medicine: J. Rachlin (96-076), 1996-1999 (Box 271, Folder 1971-1972)
  - American Enterprise Institute: C. DeMuth (92-073), 1992-1996 (Box 271, Folder 1973-1974)
  - Americas Society: L. Lamont (87-304), 1987- (Box 271, Folder 1975)
  - Blue Shield of California, Education and Research Foundation: C. Parcell (81-238), 1981-1984 (Box 271, Folder 1976-1978)
  - Blue Shield of California, Education and Research Foundation: C. Parcell (83-275), 1983-1986 (Box 272, Folder 1979-1980)
  - Boston University: R. Egdahl (79-149), 1979-1983 (Box 272, Folder 1981-1986)
  - Brigham and Women's Hospital: B. McNeil (84-080), 1984-1989 (Box 273, Folder 1987-1991)
  - National Fund for Medical Education: N. Stearns (88-286), 1988-1994 (Box 273, Folder 1992-1993)
  - National Fund for Medical Education: N. Stearns (88-286), 1988-1994 (Box 274, Folder 1994-1995)
  - RAND Corporation: R. Brook (88-221), 1988-1990 (Box 274, Folder 1996-1998)
  - RAND Corporation: R. Brook (89-299), 1989-1993 (Box 274, Folder 1999-2000)
  - RAND Corporation: R. Brook (89-299), 1989-1993 (Box 275, Folder 2001-2002)
  - RAND Corporation: R. Brook (89-058), 1989-1993 (Box 275, Folder 2003-2005)
  - Rochester Area Hospitals Corporation: W. Hall (87-029), 1987-1992 (Box 275, Folder 2006-2008)
  - Rochester Area Hospitals Corporation: W. Hall (87-029), 1987-1992 (Box 276, Folder 2009)
  - Stanford University: A. Enthoven (88-151), 1988-1994 (Box 276, Folder 2010-2013)
  - Presbyterian Hospital, Pittsburgh (222), 1954-1957 (Box 276, Folder 2014)
  - Presbyterian Hospital, Pittsburgh (223), 1958-1961 (Box 276, Folder 2015)
  - Boston University School of Medicine, Amyloid: A. Cohen-S. Cathcart (74-326), 1974-1978 (Box 277, Folder 2016)
  - Boston University School of Medicine, Aging-Kidney: L. Lowenstein (77-203), 1977-1980 (Box 277, Folder 2017)
  - Bowman Gray School of Medicine, Toxocariasis: C. Huntley (77-293), 1977-1981 (Box 277, Folder 2018)
  - Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, Transplant Antigen: T. Harris (76-233), 1976-1980 (Box 277, Folder 2019)
  - Children's Rehabilitation Institute, Trace Metals: J. Chisolm (77-303), 1977-1981 (Box 277, Folder 2020)
  - The Cleveland Clinic Foundation, Hypertension: R. Tarazi (76-026), 1976-1979 (Box 277, Folder 2021)
  - Columbia University: R. Hiatt (File Missing per JAHF) (77-285), 1977-1979 (Box 277, Folder 2022)
  - Cornell University Medical College, Transplants: R. Riggio (1972), 1972-1974 (Box 277, Folder 2023)
  - Cornell University Medical College, Transplants: R. Riggio (74-335), 1974-1977 (Box 277, Folder 2024)
  - Cornell University Medical College, Transplants: R. Riggio (77-126), 1977-1979 (Box 277, Folder 2025)
  - Cornell University Medical College Antibiotic surfactants: W. O'Leary (77-312), 1977-1980 (Box 277, Folder 2026)
  - George Washington University, Thymosin: A. Goldstein (78-016), 1978-1980 (Box 277, Folder 2027)
  - Georgetown University, Transplant Tolerance: C. Hufnagel (74-016), 1974-1978 (Box 278, Folder 2028)
  - Hahnemann Medical College, Renin-Erythropoiesis: A. Gould (77-213), 1977-1981 (Box 278, Folder 2029)
  - Health Research, Inc., Vaccine to Serum Hepatitis: J. Pert (74-025), 1974-1980 (Box 278, Folder 2030)
  - Health Research, Inc., Interferon: W. Carter (77-323), 1977-1980 (Box 278, Folder 2031)
  - Hospital for Sick Children, Insulin: J. Martin (76-036), 1976-1979 (Box 278, Folder 2032)
  - Indiana University Foundation, Cytoplasmic Inheritance: W. Nance (74-046), 1974-1978 (Box 278, Folder 2033)
  - Institute for Medical Research, Coccidioidomycosis: D. Stevens (77-043), 1977-1980 (Box 278, Folder 2034)
  - Johns Hopkins University, Lymph Therapy Immunotherapy: A. Munster (77-052), 1977-1979 (Box 278, Folder 2035)
  - Leonard Wood Memorial, Leprosy: C. Reich (78-028), 1978-1981 (Box 279, Folder 2036)
  - Manhattan Eye, Ear and Throat Hospital: C. Kelman (no grant number), 1963-1972 (Box 279, Folder 2037-2039)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Lung Function: H. Kazemi (77-063), 1977-1980 (Box 279, Folder 2040)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Brain Function: R. Wurtman (77-156), 1977-1978 (Box 279, Folder 2041)
  - Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, Cellular-Bone: R. Good (77-015), 1977-1980 (Box 279, Folder 2042)
  - Medical University of South Carolina, Gastric mucosa: F. Pittman (74-376), 1974-1980 (Box 280, Folder 2043)
  - Michael Reese Medical Center, Hormone secretion: L. Sherwood (76-206), 1976-1981 (Box 280, Folder 2044)
  - Montefiore Hospital, Urea-Electrochemical: S. Yao (77-073), 1977-1980 (Box 280, Folder 2045)
  - Mt. Sinai School of Medicine, Herpes virus: J. Schwartz (76-243), 1976-1980 (Box 280, Folder 2046)
  - Mt. Sinai School of Medicine, Hepatitis: F. Paronetto (76-253), 1976-1980 (Box 280, Folder 2047)
  - National Jewish Hospital, Asthma: D. Shucard (77-333), 1977-1982 (Box 280, Folder 2048)
  - New York Medical College, Drug reactions: M. Fellner (76-065), 1975-1979 (Box 280, Folder 2049)
  - New York Medical College, Drug reactions: M. Fellner (76-065) Separated media: Slides of reactions to drugs, circa 1975; 2014:023:019; 7 slides (Box 2014:023:019, Folder 2049)
  - New York University Medical Center, Hepatitis vaccine: S. Krugman (76-263), 1976-1979 (Box 280, Folder 2050)
  - Pennsylvania Hospital, Renal: C. Wolf (77-222), 1977-1979 (Box 280, Folder 2051)
  - Pennsylvania State University, Diabetes Mellitus: C. Lang (77-166), 1977-1980 (Box 281, Folder 2052)
  - Peter Bent Brigham Hospital, Heart attacks: E. Braunwald (76-076), 1976-1979 (Box 281, Folder 2053)
  - Research Foundation of SUNY, Gallstone: B. Gardner (77-026), 1977-1981 (Box 281, Folder 2054)
  - Temple University, Artificial heart valves: J. Davila (no grant number), 1964-1966 (Box 281, Folder 2055)
  - Tufts University School of Medicine, Cholera: G. Sharp (78-046), 1978-1980 (Box 281, Folder 2056)
  - Tulane University School of Medicine, Neuro-Inner ear: C. Norris (77-233), 1977-1980 (Box 281, Folder 2057)
  - University of Alabama, Birmingham, Candidiasis: L. Montes (77-083), 1977-1981 (Box 281, Folder 2058)
  - University of California, Davis, Intravascular coagulation: C. Abildgaard (76-086), 1976-1980 (Box 281, Folder 2059)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, Gallstones: R. Tompkins (74-415), 1974-1978 (Box 281, Folder 2060)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, Thyroid: D. Solomon (no grant number), 1973 (Box 282, Folder 2061)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, Nerve growth: F. Wolfgram (77-176), 1977-1982 (Box 282, Folder 2062)
  - University of California, San Diego, Gastric hormone: M. Orloff (77-243), 1977-1980 (Box 282, Folder 2063)
  - University of California, San Francisco, Auto-immunity: A. Ammann (76-106), 1976-1980 (Box 282, Folder 2064)
  - Baptist Memorial Hospital, Hepatitis: W. Rightsel (no grant number), 1971-1974 (Box 282, Folder 2065)
  - Barnes Hospital, Hepatic disease: J. Grisham (no grant number), 1973 (Box 282, Folder 2066)
  - Baylor College of Medicine, Vaccines: J. Knox (no grant number), 1970 (Box 282, Folder 2067)
  - Beth Israel, Hormone secretion: L. Sherwood (no grant number), 1972 (Box 282, Folder 2068)
  - Bio Research Institute, Inc., Muscular dystrophy (no grant number), 1972 (Box 282, Folder 2069)
  - Blodgett Memorial Hospita, Implants: A. Swanson (no grant number), 1971 (Box 282, Folder 2070)
  - Case Western University, Inner ear: V. Jordan (no grant number), 1972 (Box 282, Folder 2071)
  - Cedars-Sinai Medical Center, Plasma lipids: R. Caren (no grant number), 1974 (Box 282, Folder 2072)
  - Chicago Wesley Memorial Hospital: L. Head (no grant number), 1970 (Box 282, Folder 2073)
  - Children's Hospital, Dental enamel: M. Glimcher (574-A), 1964-1967 (Box 282, Folder 2074)
  - Children's Hospital, Dental enamel: M. Glimcher (574-B), 1967-1971 (Box 282, Folder 2075)
  - Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, Bioengineering: J. Kinney (514-A), 1967-1970 (Box 282, Folder 2076)
  - Cornell University Medical College, Cryobiology and cryosurgery: F. Daniels (539-A), 1966-1969 (Box 283, Folder 2077)
  - Cornell University Medical College, Cryobiology and cryosurgery: F. Daniels (539-B), 1969-1971 (Box 283, Folder 2078)
  - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology, Nephrology: J. Merrill (76), 1966 (Box 283, Folder 2079)
  - George Washington University School of Medicine, Mycoplasma: T. Brown (773-A), 1966-1970 (Box 283, Folder 2080)
  - Hahnemann Medical College, Intestinal function: J. Howard (no grant number), 1969-1970 (Box 283, Folder 2081)
  - Harvard School of Public Health, Blood substitutes: R. Geyer (726-A), 1968-1971 (Box 283, Folder 2082)
  - Hospital Research and Educational Trust, Nursing home accreditation: E. Crosby (no grant number), 1968 (Box 283, Folder 2083)
  - Jacksonville Hospitals Educational Program (no grant number), 1964 (Box 283, Folder 2084)
  - Medical College of Pennsylvania, Ultrasound: B. Sigel (177), 1967-1970 (Box 283, Folder 2085)
  - Presbyterian-University of Pennsylvania Medical Center, Diabetes: J. Kitchell-L. Meltzer (409), 1965-1968 (Box 283, Folder 2086)
  - Providence Hospital, Fibrin biochemistry: L. Sauvage (503), 1968-1971 (Box 283, Folder 2087)
  - St. Barnabas Hospital, Cryosurgery: M. Ricklan (658-A), 1962-1965 (Box 284, Folder 2088)
  - St. Barnabas Hospital, Cryogenic surgery: I Cooper (658-B), 1965-1968 (Box 284, Folder 2089-2090)
  - St. Barnabas Hospital, Cryosurgery: I. Cooper (659), 1969-1972 (Box 284, Folder 2091)
  - St. Barnabas Hospital, Thrombosis: S. Gollub (257), 1965-1967 (Box 284, Folder 2092)
  - St. Joseph Hospital (Tacoma), Sputum: J. Billingsley (no grant number), 1975 (Box 284, Folder 2093)
  - Temple University Health Sciences Center, Conference: F. Urbach (no grant number), 1966-1967 (Box 284, Folder 2094)
  - Third International Congress of Plastic Surgery: L. Backus (290), 1963-1964 (Box 284, Folder 2095)
  - The Transplantation Society, Conference: J. Converse (296), 1968 (Box 284, Folder 2096)
  - University of Chicago Division of Biological Sciences, Surgical stapler: P. Moulder (430), 1966-1969 (Box 285, Folder 2097-2098)
  - Unidentified Early Grant Reports, 1970s (Box 285, Folder 2099)
  - Blood Research Institute, Inc., Plasma proteins: R. Pennell (352), 1964-1967 (Box 285, Folder 2100)
  - Blood Research Institute, Inc., Plasma proteins: R. Pennell (351), 1967-1970 (Box 285, Folder 2101)
  - Blood Research, Inc., Adipose tissue extracts: H. Antoniades (568), 1970-1973 (Box 285, Folder 2102)
  - Children's Hospital Medical Center, Bone marrow: L. Diamond (53), 1960-1965 (Box 285, Folder 2103)
  - Children's Hospital Medical Center, Extracorporeal Oxygenation: W. Bernhard (576), 1970-1974 (Box 285, Folder 2104)
  - Children's Hospital Medical Center, Extracorporeal oxygenation: W. Bernhard (576), 1970-1974 (Box 285, Folder 2105)
  - Children's Hospital Medical Center, Dental enamel: J. Seyer (574-C), 1970-1974 (Box 286, Folder 2106)
  - Children's Hospital Medical Center, Dental enamel: J. Seyer (574-C), 1970-1974 (Box 286, Folder 2107)
  - Children's Hospital Medical Center, Joint replacement: M. Glimcher (575), 1970-1973 (Box 286, Folder 2108)
  - Creighton University, Alimentary lipemia: J. Sullivan (no grant number), 1968 (Box 286, Folder 2109)
  - George Washington University, Sera: G. Wright (568-B), 1970-1973 (Box 286, Folder 2110)
  - Georgetown College, Vitamin D: J. Canary (366), 1966-1969 (Box 286, Folder 2111)
  - Georgetown University Hospital, Fat metabolism: R. Coffey (87), 1961-1964 (Box 286, Folder 2112)
  - Georgetown University, Shock: J. Dillon-R. Coffey (587), 1970-1972 (Box 286, Folder 2113)
  - Grace Hospital (Detroit), Gall bladder: R. DeBusk (92), 1954-1958 (Box 286, Folder 2114)
  - Harvard School of Public Health, Fiber-optic techniques: B. Lown (598-A), 1965-1968 (Box 287, Folder 2115)
  - Harvard School of Public Health, Fiber-optic techniques (598-B), 1968-1970 (Box 287, Folder 2116)
  - Harvard School of Public Health, Artificial blood (726-B), 1971-1972 (Box 287, Folder 2117)
  - Harvard School of Public Health, Artificial blood: P. Geyer (726-C), 1972-1974 (Box 287, Folder 2118)
  - Harvard School of Public Health, Blood substitutes: R. Geyer (74-357) (726-D), 1974-1976 (Box 287, Folder 2119)
  - Hospital for Sick Children (Toronto), Hepatic disease: A. Sass-Kortsak (599-A), 1962-1965 (Box 287, Folder 2120)
  - Hospital for Sick Children (Toronto), Copper metabolism: A. Sass-Kortsak (599-B), 1965-1969 (Box 287, Folder 2121)
  - Hospital for Sick Children (Toronto), Copper metabolism: A. Sass-Kortsak (599-C), 1969-1972 (Box 287, Folder 2122)
  - Leonard Wood Memorial, Leprosy: C. Reich (74-066) (763-B), 1974-1977 (Box 287, Folder 2123)
  - The Mary Imogene Bassett Hospital, Leukemia: H. Spencer-J. Ferrebee (134), 1962-1967 (Box 288, Folder 2124)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Lipids: A. Leaf (137), 1956-1963 (Box 288, Folder 2125)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Calcification: M. Glimcher (138), 1958-1961 (Box 288, Folder 2126)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Electrolytes: A. Leaf (139), 1959-1965 (Box 288, Folder 2127)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Mineralization: M. Glimcher (140), 1961-1965 (Box 288, Folder 2128)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Pancreas: G. Nardi (379), 1966-1969 (Box 288, Folder 2129)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Pancreas: G. Nardi (380), 1969-1970 (Box 288, Folder 2130)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Electrolytes: A. Leaf (480), 1963-1966 (Box 288, Folder 2131)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, Aldosterone: A. Leaf (481), 1966-1969 (Box 288, Folder 2132)
  - National Orthopoedic and Rehabilitation Hospital, Mycoplasma: H. Clark (74-125) (773-C), 1974-1977 (Box 288, Folder 2133)
  - New York University Medical Center, Streptococcal Antigens (792-A), 1969-1972 (Box 289, Folder 2134)
  - New York University Medical Center, Autoimmunity: F. Rapaport (792-B), 1972-1976 (Box 289, Folder 2135)